MARK EKE

With over 6 years of development experience, I am a proactive, clever, and dedicated engineer and leader. From concept to deployment, I've created software solutions for commercial use cases. I am an expert Python and JavaScript programmer. I've developed e-commerce solutions, finance solutions, and other software solutions.

15 Victory Layout, Enugu Enugu State, Nigeria, NG. +234706518693

ekemarkonyekachi22@gmail.com Github: https://github.com/kramstyles

Website: https://markeke.dev

EXPERIENCE

Decagon, Benin — Software Engineer

JANUARY 2022 - DATE

- A member of a team that is developing a Financial Solution for a Recycle-Pay project.
- Built projects with React.js, Python, and Javascript, Django and DRF.
- Handled Database Management System with SQL like MySQL, **Postgres**
- Read and managed data gotten from external API or XML calls
- Experience writing unit and integration test

Digital Dreams, Enugu — Software Engineer and Tutor

MAY 2019 - JANUARY 2022

- A member of a team developing, architecting and implementing backend APIs for a School Management system.
- Taught over 150+ individuals HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python, JQuery, PHP, Wordpress etc
- Built websites using Python Flask and PHP.
- Worked with Multiple Languages and Frameworks which include Python (Flask, PyQT5, Pyside, Django), Bootstrap, Materialize, PHP, Wordpress, Javascript, Jquery, Typescript, Ionic, Angular 5 etc
- Handled scheduled tasks with cron jobs.
- Read and clean data using Pandas and Numpy. Visualized data using Matplotlib

GOG Computers, Abia — Software Engineer & IT Personnel

JANUARY 2013 - JANUARY 2019

- Built responsive websites using HTML, CSS and JQuery.
- Created Online and E-commerce solutions using Wordpress.
- Worked with Microsoft Office Software like MS Word, Powerpoint, Excel, Access, Publisher.
- Exposure to agile methodologies.

Michael Okpara University, Umudike, Abia — Assistant IT Personnel

FEBRUARY 2016 - DECEMBER 2018

- Worked with Programming languages like Pascal and Visual Basic
- Exposure to Front End Technology

TECHNOLOGIES

- HTML 5
- CSS 3
- Bootstrap
- Javascript
- **JQuery**
- **AJAX**
- Lottiefiles
- React
- Redux
- React Hooks
- Python
- Flask
- PyQT5
- PySide2
- Django
- Django Rest Framework
- Wordpress
- E-Commerce
- API
- Payment-Integration
- MvSQL
- Sqlite3
- Postgresql
- **Pandas**
- Numpy
- Matplotlib
- Tensorflow
- Ionic Framework
- Angular 5
- **Typescript**
- Docker

PROJECTS

ATLAS:

Built using Python & PyQT5, Atlas is a software that mainly reduces the data consumption of your operating system. It also displays important system information, help manage running and background processes, show battery time (time to fully charge and time left)..

Technologies Used - Python, PyQt5, PySide2

Link: https://github.com/KramStyles/atlas

AURACLE DIGITAL:

A digital marketing website for a firm with over 10 years of expertise in developing and implementing winning communication strategies for a variety of businesses and sectors in Nigeria.

Technologies Used - HTML5, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Wordpress

Link: https://auraclelimited.com

DIGITAL DREAMS PLUGINS:

An application that housed some of the common plugins used by digital dreams staff to work on a daily basis. You can read and clean massive data of students and guardians, from excel or csv sheets to installable phone numbers (VCF) in one click and lots more.

Technologies Used: Python, Pandas, Numpy, Data science, Bootstrap

Link: http://digitaldreamstudios.net/plugins/

BBK HAIRS:

An e-commerce solution for a one-stop shop for beauty supplies and equipment known to offer a variety of solutions for all of your beauty and salon essentials.

Technologies Used: HTML5, CSS, Javascript, Payment API, AJax etc

Link: https://bbkhairs.com

PLUSMIR:

Plusmir is a financial solution built using Python which allows users to make payments for subscriptions (monthly or weekly). It involves automation which calculates profits based on the amount used to subscribe.

Technologies Used - HTML5, CSS, JS, Payment Integration (Paystack

- Netlify
- Heroku
- Jira
- Version Control with Git and Github.
- Test-Driven
 Development.

and VoguePay), Python, Flask, Automation

Link: https://plus.markeke.dev

PACE POLLS:

An advanced poll created for The Pacesetter Frontier Online Magazine which solved their problem of costly monthly subscriptions to online polling services.

Technologies Used: Python3 (Flask), Javascript, Bootstrap, SQLite.

Link: https://polls.pacesetterfrontier.com

PACESETTER FRONTIER MAGAZINE:

A digital magazine for The Pacesetter Frontier Magazine; a privately owned, quarterly published, multimedia, multi-connect, cosmopolitan, print and online magazine established in 2003 and based in Enugu with a market audience and base cutting across the Southeast and Southsouth geopolitical zones of Nigeria.

Technologies Used: HTML5, CSS, JS, Wordpress, Python3 (Flask)

Link: https://pacesetterfrontier.com

PREMIUM GAMES OFFICIAL:

A Sport Events software solution for Premium Games. A company committed to providing participants with the opportunity to develop athletically and personally in a positive, supportive and safe environment.

Technologies Used: Python3 , Woocommerce API, Bootstrap, SQLite.

Link: https://premiumgames.markeke.dev

HEADLINES:

A news feed app that fetches accurate and recent information from top news agencies in the world and displays them with links to the direct news source.

Technologies Used: Python3 ,API and XML Parser, Bootstrap, SQLite.

Link: https://headlines.markeke.dev

RAYMOND SCHOOLS:

A school management application used for student registration, student and staff login, checking and printing of results and sending messages to guardians.

Technologies Used: Python , API and XML Parser, Bootstrap, CSS.

Link: http://digitaldreamstudios.net/raymond/

BERRY MEDIC:

An appointment booking solution with responsive calendars and optimized booking system for a certified Community health physician with a fellowship from the West African College of Physicians and a certification from Monash University on Food as Medicine.

Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Wordpress

Link: https://berrymedic.com

SEDES SAPIENSIA:

A school management application used for student registration, student and staff login, checking and printing of results and sending messages to guardians.

Technologies Used: Python, API and XML Parser, Bootstrap, CSS.

Link: http://digitaldreamstudios.net/sedessapiensia/

... AND LOTS MORE ...

EDUCATION

Michael Okpara University of Agriculture, Umudike — B.Sc

OCTOBER 2013 - NOVEMBER 2017

Second Class Upper - Bachelor of Science Degree in Computer Science